Guide to the Randolph Crump Miller Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Alphabetical Files, Series III
  - Grace, the Doctrine of: Its Biblical Interpretation (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - Graduate School Papers by Miller, 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Gremlins and Christianity (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - Half of His Religion at Three (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - Holidays, writings re.: Christmas Thoughts (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - Holidays, writings re.: Thoughts on Thanksgiving, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - How I Became a Religious Educator--Or Did I? (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - Human Relations and Christian Education (Box 11, Folder 129)
  - A Humanistic Approach to Theism, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 130)
  - Impressions of Peter Abelard, 1940 (Box 11, Folder 131)
  - An Introduction to Christian Education: Draft 1 - Chapters 1-7 (Box 11, Folder 132)
  - An Introduction to Christian Education: Draft 1 - Chapters 8-16 (Box 12, Folder 133)
  - An Introduction to Christian Education: Draft 1 - Chapters 17-25, bibliography (Box 12, Folder 134)
  - An Introduction to Christian Education: Draft 2 - Chapters 1-7 (Box 12, Folder 135)
  - An Introduction to Christian Education: Draft 2 - Chapters 8-16 (Box 12, Folder 136)
  - An Introduction to Christian Education: Draft 2 - Chapters 17-25, bibliography (Box 12, Folder 137)
  - James, William, writings re. (Box 13, Folder 138)
  - Jazz, writings re.:Freedom and Jazz, The Witness, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 139)
  - Jazz, writings re.:Theology of Jazz., n.d (Box 13, Folder 139)
  - The Jesus of History and the Church (Box 13, Folder 140)
  - Kant, writings re.:Immanuel Kant's chapter on the Ideal of Pure Reason (Box 13, Folder 141)
  - Lessons the Children Like: Practical Suggestions for Church School Teachers, The Churchman, 1943 Jan 1 (Box 13, Folder 142)
  - Liberalism, writings re.:Has Liberalism a Theology?, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - Liberalism, writings re.: Liberalism is Not Dead! (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - Liberalism, writings re.: Who Are the Liberals? (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - Liberalism, writings re.: Liberalism: Method or Creed?, 1936 (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - Linguistic Analysis and Religious Instruction, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Linguistics, writings re.: Linguistic Models and Christian Education (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - Linguistics, writings re.: Linguistic Philosophy and Religious Education (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - Litany for Understanding (used at installation of Brenda Pelc-Faszcza) (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - A Litany for Union (adapted from Christian Century, 1938 Mar 9, with additions by RCM) (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - The Living Church (ed. by RCM), 1942 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Man Has a Future (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Marriage, The Completeness of Life Through, 1930 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Metaphysics, writings re.: A Review of A. E. Taylor's The Faith of a Moralist, 1933 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - The Ministry - A Partnership, The Messenger, 1953 Jun 16 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - Ministry - Ordination, writings re.: Do We Need an Ordained Ministry? (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - Ministry - Ordination, writings re.: The Meaning of the Ordained Ministry (Box 14, Folder 152)
  - A Modern Quest for God (Box 14, Folder 153)
  - Moral Behavior for Christians (Box 14, Folder 154)
  - Morning Prayer, The Witness, 1962 Feb 15 (Box 14, Folder 155)
  - The Mystery of God, The Witness, 1950 Apr 13 (Box 14, Folder 156)
  - New Challenges in Religious Education, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 157)
  - New Curriculum Under Way, The Churchman, 1949 May 15 (Box 14, Folder 158)
  - The New Naturalism and Christianity, 1940 (Box 14, Folder 159)
  - The New Testament and Church Unity (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - New Thinking in Christian Education, Concordia Theological Review, 1965 Feb (Box 14, Folder 161)
  - Not by Bread Alone: Discussion Points (Box 14, Folder 162)
  - Nurture Corner, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 163)
  - O, Principle of Concretion, The Chronicle, 1937 Jan (Box 14, Folder 164)
  - The Objective of Christian Education (Box 14, Folder 165)
  - Old Themes in New Dress (Box 14, Folder 166)
  - Our Common Biblical Heritage, The Witness, 1948 Nov 25 (Box 14, Folder 167)
  - Our Faith and How We Communicate It, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 168)
  - Overcoming Our Troubles, The Pulpit, 1945 Apr (Box 14, Folder 169)
  - Parents, writings re.: Youth Considers Parents as People, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 170)
  - Parents, writings re.: Speech manuscript, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 170)
  - Pearson, Karl, writings re.: Karl Pearson's Theory of Knowledge, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 171)
  - Philosophy of Life: Lecture Notes (Box 14, Folder 172)
  - Plato, writings re.: Philebus (Box 14, Folder 173)
  - Plato, writings re.: Republic (Box 14, Folder 173)
  - The Prayer Book and the Red Network: A Volume Which is "Profoundly Subversive", The Churchmen, 1945 Nov 15 (Box 14, Folder 174)
  - Prayer in Wartime, The Christian Century, 1942 Nov 25 (Box 14, Folder 175)
  - Prayers, miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 176)
  - Preaching, The Theological Content of (outline of course) (Box 15, Folder 177)
  - Process Theology, writings re.: Empiricism and Process Theology (Box 15, Folder 178)
  - Process Theology, writings re.: Process, Evil and God (Box 15, Folder 178)
  - Process Theology, writings re.: Readings in Process Thinking (Box 15, Folder 178)
  - Prophets, writings re.: A Congressional Investigation of the Prophets (Box 15, Folder 179)
  - Prophets, writings re.: God and the Nations (Box 15, Folder 179)
  - Prophets, writings re.: The Relevance of the Prophets (Box 15, Folder 179)
  - Psychology of Religion, writings re.: A Comparative Study of the Psychological Needs Answered By Fundamentalism and Modernism, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 180)
  - Psychology of Religion, writings re.: Humanism and Religion, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 180)
  - Psychology of Religion, writings re.: Psychological Criticisms of Religion, God and Prayer, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 181)
  - Psychology of Religion, writings re.: A Psychological Approach to the Problem of Religious Disillusionment, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 181)
  - Psychology of Religion, writings re.: The Idea of Yahweh in the Light of Modern Epistemological and Psychological Studies (Box 15, Folder 181)
  - Religious Education: Some Favorite Issues (RCM, ed.), 1958-1978 (Box 15, Folder 182)
  - Religious Education in the U.S.A., Writings re. (by RCM and others) (Box 15, Folder 183)
  - Religious Education Today and Tomorrow, Reflection, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 184)
  - Religion Is Any Subject, 1957, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 185)
  - Resetting Our Sights in Christian Education, Concordia Theological Monthly, 1965 Mar (Box 15, Folder 186)
  - Seabury Series, 1949-1955, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 187)
  - Secondary Schools and Christian Education: Facing the Mystery of Middle Adolescence, The Churchman, 1943 Aug 1 (Box 15, Folder 188)
  - Second-Rate Preachers and the Seminaries (Box 15, Folder 189)
  - Sermons, miscellaneous, 1933-1938, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 190)
  - Sermons, miscellaneous, 1942-1951, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 191)
  - Sermons, writings re.: Bible (Box 15, Folder 192)
  - Sermons, writings re.: Christian Education (Box 15, Folder 193)
  - Sermons, writings re.: Church (Box 15, Folder 194)
  - Sermons, writings re.: Church Year (Box 15, Folder 195)
  - Sermons, writings re.: Dialogue (Box 16, Folder 196)
  - Sermons, writings re.: God and the Nations (Box 16, Folder 197)
  - Sermons, writings re.: Love (Box 16, Folder 198)
  - Sermons, writings re.: Practical and Personal (Box 16, Folder 199)
  - Sermons, writings re.: Prayer Book (Box 16, Folder 200)
  - Sermons, writings re.: Social (Box 16, Folder 201)
  - The Shakespeare of the Prayer Book, The Southern Churchman, 1949 Aug 13 (Box 16, Folder 202)
  - Some Thoughts on College Problems, 1937 or 1938 (Box 16, Folder 203)
  - Son of Man (Box 16, Folder 204)
  - Speeches: Editors Section - How do we define "Commitment" in relation to children and youth? (Box 16, Folder 205)
  - Speeches: Children's Section - The family speaks: The Church Listens, I. and II. (Box 16, Folder 205)
  - Spinoza, writings re.: Religion and Spinoza, 1932 (Box 16, Folder 206)
  - Spirituality and the Religious Educator, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 207)
  - Sprachmodelle und Religionsunterricht, Theologia Practica, 1968 Apr (Box 16, Folder 208)
  - Streamlining the Church: The Same Destination But Better Equipment, The Churchman, 1942 (Box 16, Folder 209)
  - Sunday School, writings re.: Should I Force My Child to Attend Church School? (Box 16, Folder 210)
  - Sunday School, writings re.: Report on St. Paul's Program of Christian Education (Box 16, Folder 210)
  - Syllabi from courses taught at Church Divinity School of the Pacific, 1947-1948, no date (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Systematic Theology / Religion and Contemporary Philosophy: General Reading Report, 1933 (Box 16, Folder 211)
  - The Teacher Teaches - Radio Broadcast, Teacher Training Institute, 1954 Oct 12 (Box 16, Folder 212)
  - Teaching to Create Faith (Box 16, Folder 212)
  - The Teaching Mission of the Church (Box 16, Folder 213)
  - Temple, William, writings re. and class notes: Statesmanship in the Church (Box 16, Folder 214)
  - Temple, William, writings re. and class notes: William Temple: Anglican Bishop, Social Reformer (Box 16, Folder 214)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: William Temple? When he first sought ordination, he was refused (Box 16, Folder 214)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: For the World of Tomorrow (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Some Thoughts on Theological Education (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Standards of Instruction in Theological Schools (included in Minutes of the Fourth Pacific Regional Conference of the American Association of Theological Schools) (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theological Education for Tomorrow's Church (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theological Education for Tomorrow's World (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: (This folder also includes Yale's Committee on Professional Studies Study of Grading Practices, 1954-1955 - listing of grade distributions) (Box 16, Folder 215)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theologies and Clinics, The Churchman, 1937 Mar 15 (Easter) (Box 16, Folder 216)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology, writings re.:The Christian Hope in Relation to the Church Situation Today (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology, writings re.:The Doctrine of Grace: Its Biblical Interpretation (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology, writings re.:Modern Conceptions of God (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology, writings re.: The Relationship of Theology to the Understanding of Children (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology, writings re.: Value-Theory and Empirical Theology (Box 16, Folder 217)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology, American, writings re.: Religious Realism in America (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology, American, writings re.: Some Trends in American Theology (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology in Transition (Box 16, Folder 218)
  - Theological Education, writings re.:Theology and Religious Education (Box 16, Folder 219)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology and the Future of Religious Education, Religious Education, 1977 Jan-Feb (Box 16, Folder 220)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Theology in the Background (Box 17, Folder 221)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Things Are Happening at the Pacific, The Witness, 1949 Jan 20 (Box 17, Folder 222)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: The Upper Room, writings for (Box 17, Folder 223)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: What is Christianity?, 1939 (Box 17, Folder 224)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: What the Seminaries are Trying to Do, The Los Angeles Churchman, 1941 Mar (Box 17, Folder 225)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: What the Young Cleric Studies, The Los Angeles Churchman, 1938 Jan (Box 17, Folder 226)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: "Why I Don't Go to Church": Comments on a Subject Still Being Discussed, The Churchman, 1941 Mar 1 (Box 17, Folder 227)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Why Morning Prayer (Box 17, Folder 228)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Why the Holy Catholic Church is Protestant (Box 17, Folder 229)
  - Theological Education, writings re.:Why the Protestant Episcopal Church is Catholic (Box 17, Folder 229)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Weighman's Use of Empirical Method (includes correspondence with Wieman) (Box 17, Folder 230)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Women in the Church (Commencement Address, St. Margaret's House, June 4, 1952) (Box 17, Folder 231)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Worship and Process Philosophy, 1976-1980 (Box 17, Folder 232)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: Yale Interprets the News, 1952 Sep 28; 1953 Apr 5 (Box 17, Folder 233)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: YMCA Assembly on Work with Youth: A Working Faith for the YMCA (Box 17, Folder 234)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: YMCA Assembly on Work with Youth: The Responsibility of Our Role in Christian Education, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 234)
  - Theological Education, writings re.: YMCA Lectures, 1950s: I. How Theology Affects Education (Box 17, Folder 235)
  - Theological Education, writings re.:YMCA Lectures, 1950s: II. The Bible in Today's World (Box 17, Folder 235)
  - Theological Education, writings re.:YMCA Lectures, 1950s: III. A Working Faith for the YMCA (Box 17, Folder 235)
  - Theological Education, writings re.:You Need the Church (edited for Forward Movement), 1952 or 1953 (Box 17, Folder 236)
- Scrapbooks, Series IV
  - 9 scrapbooks containing miscellaneous articles, reviews and biographical information, 1935-1987. (Box 17, Folder 237-239)
  - Scrapbooks (continued) (Box 18, Folder 240-241)
- Notes, Series V
  - Theology and Moral values; Christian Education around the world (Box 18, Folder 242)
  - New Haven Memorial Society; Soaring; When family is family (Box 18, Folder 243)
  - Secularism and Process theology (Box 18, Folder 244)
  - Talking about God; The State of the disciple; The Use and misuse of Religious Language (Box 18, Folder 245)
  - Pastoral Prayers; Wartime prayers; Prayers for the Jews and Christians (Box 18, Folder 246)
  - Religious Education in Community; The Church and Christian Education; Tweedy (1868-1953) (Box 18, Folder 247)
  - The fragile earth; Women and resurrection; The Sabbath (Box 18, Folder 248)
  - Christian Education as Theological discipline and Method; Commencement address: Women in the Church; How do we decide what we believe (Box 18, Folder 249)
  - If I should die before I wake up; Is loyalty to the church enough; Man's hope (Box 19, Folder 250)
  - Lent to the Episcopalian; Fundamentals of the Christian Teachings (Box 19, Folder 251)
  - A biblical dictator; The only gospel; Man, good and evil (Box 19, Folder 252)
  - God the source of power; Decently and in order; Riding two horses (Box 19, Folder 253)
  - The family speaks out; Revelation, relevance and relationship; How the Church can help families (Box 19, Folder 254)
  - Where is your loyalty; Vocational Giving; Is repentance artificial (Box 19, Folder 255)
  - Negative and Positive religion; Whose Children are we; There will be some changes made (Box 19, Folder 256)
  - The Psychology of hate; Lift up your hearts; Search your hearts (Box 19, Folder 257)
  - Looking unto God; This is my body; Talking to God (Box 20, Folder 258)
  - Liberalism is natural; Your Star; When religion meant something (Box 20, Folder 259)
  - God as idea and as living; Unless God blesses the deed; My first Communion (Box 20, Folder 260)
  - Lincoln, the war and ourselves; The teaching function of the Church; You and the Church (Box 20, Folder 261)
  - Questions Jesus asked; The Bible speaks to our day; Do you believe in the coming of Jesus (Box 20, Folder 262)
  - A New year; Letters but no Post office; God and Christmas (Box 20, Folder 263)
  - Make the lost world your home (Box 21, Folder 264)
  - Is the world getting any better; Does the Church bury it's talents; Why do you give thanks (Box 21, Folder 265)
  - The offering to the Jerusalem Church; Cheap and Costly grace (Box 21, Folder 266)
  - Moral behavior for Christians (Box 21, Folder 267)
  - Wise and foolish Virgins; A Christian Fellowship in a secular world; The resurrection of the dead (Box 21, Folder 268)
  - Shakespeare of the prayer book; As a father pitieth his children; Do you believe in immortality (Box 21, Folder 269)
  - 65th Anniversary of Religious Education; The Lord's Prayer; Practical Personal Religion (Box 21, Folder 270)
  - The testing of your faith; Major notes of our faith; The Ministry (Box 21, Folder 271)
  - The Kings Highway; The art of dying; What is the name of God (Box 21, Folder 272)
  - A Platform for free discussion of Religious Education Issues and their bearing on Education (Box 21, Folder 273)
  - Untitled Papers or notes (Box 21, Folder 274)
  - Newspaper clippings -Extracts (Box 21, Folder 275)
  - Articles about RCM; two postcards written to his children (Box 24, Folder 293)
- Audio-Visual Material, Series VI
  - A life in Education; A Conversation with Randolph Crump Miller; Video Tape Part 1; A Personal Spiritual Pilgrimage (Box 22, Folder 276)
  - Video tape Part 3; Mapping the Flow of Religious Education (Box 22, Folder 277)
  - Video Tape Part 4; The Role of Theology in Religious Education (Box 22, Folder 278)
  - Video Tape Part 5; Cutting Edge Issues in Religious Education (Box 22, Folder 279)
  - Audio Tape Part 1; Theology of Jazz (Box 23, Folder 280)
  - Audio Tape Part 2; Theology of Jazz (Box 23, Folder 281)
  - Audio Tape; untitled (Box 23, Folder 282)
  - Audio Tape; untitled (Box 23, Folder 283)
- Biographical Material, Series VII
  - Correspondence - general, 1952-1974, 1984, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 298)
  - Correspondence re. Miller's appointment as Writer-Consultant to the Divinity of Curriculum Development, Protestant Episcopal Church (Box 25, Folder 299)
  - Letters primarily to RCM, 1941-1981 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    Scope and Contents
    Including from Seelye Bixler, Douglas Macintosh, Nicholas Piediscalzi, Harold B. Whiteman, Jr, and others.
  - Biographical documentation (Box 25, Folder 300)
  - Newspaper clippings, articles, brochures about Miller, 1947-1964, 1982, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 301)
  - Re. Miller's faculty appointment and retirement (Box 25, Folder 302)
  - Articles about RCM, 1942-1983 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - Trbutes to RCM by Iris Cully, Ruth A. Dudley, Sara Little, William Muehl, 1978, no date (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - News clippings about RCM, 1977, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - Notices of lectures; testimonial from Religious Education Association, 1964, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Notice of RCM as Fellow Emeritus for life of Timothy Dwight College, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 18)